<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Graveyard on Michael Gleicher's Web Page</title><link>/pages/graveyard/</link><description>Recent content in Graveyard on Michael Gleicher's Web Page</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 18:12:02 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/pages/graveyard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2009 Home Page</title><link>/pages/graveyard/2009-home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/graveyard/2009-home/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is an Ancient (2009) version of my home page.
Page last modified on July 16, 2009, at 11:52 AM.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>advice-bibliographies</title><link>/pages/graveyard/bibliographies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/graveyard/bibliographies/</guid><description>Reading is an important part of doing research.
Part of the problem is keeping track of what you&amp;rsquo;ve read. I strongly recommend that you keep a bibliography (database) of everything you read that is research/work related.
Update: back when I wrote this, there weren&amp;rsquo;t any good technological solutions to this. That has changed a bit. As of 2020, I am using Zotero. Medeley is in some ways a better alternative, but there are issues that the company that runs it treats your data in an unacceptable manner.</description></item><item><title>courses-games10announce</title><link>/pages/graveyard/courses-games10announce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/graveyard/courses-games10announce/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a historic announcement for the 2010 Computer Games Class. It was the first time I taught the class.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pre-2010 Papers By Topic</title><link>/pages/graveyard/oldpapersbytopic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/graveyard/oldpapersbytopic/</guid><description>Selected Historical Publications (Papers, Talks, Videos), Organized by Topic This page has not been updated since 2010! Please See http://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~gleicher/Papers for an up to date list!
This list is not necessarily complete, and hasn&amp;rsquo;t been updated in quite some time. For a more complete list, check the automatically generated lists of papers, talks, or videos. This is mainly things from the past few years.
1. Visualization and Protein Science 1.1 Bioinformatics Visualizations (Sequences) 1.</description></item><item><title>Re-cinematography</title><link>/pages/graveyard/re-cinematography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/graveyard/re-cinematography/</guid><description>Re-Cinematography was our circa 2007 video stabilization system. At the time, it was way better than anything else. It inspired later techniques, notably our 2009 3D Warping technique, and our 2010 Subspace Warping technique (which evolved into the Adobe Warp Stabilizer.).
Re-Cinematography pushed the limits of what could be done with 2D global warps (using a single, 8 parameter projective warp over the entire image). The later techniques (e.g. SubSpace Video Stabilization (ToG 2011)) went beyond it by allowing for warping the image, not just global deformations.</description></item><item><title>Visualization 2010 Course Announcement</title><link>/pages/graveyard/vis10announce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/graveyard/vis10announce/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the historic announcement for the first time I offered a visualization class in 2010. It was an experiment that keeps going to this day (2020 as I write this). It&amp;rsquo;s pretty interesting that even at the beginning, I had the same ideas as to the goals of the class.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>