<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mike Gleicher's Home Page on Michael Gleicher's Web Page</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Mike Gleicher's Home Page on Michael Gleicher's Web Page</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding Control Frames in Multi-Camera Robot Telemanipulation (talk video)</title><link>/video/2022_control_frames/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2022_control_frames/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Student Start</title><link>/pages/student-start/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 16:41:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>/pages/student-start/</guid><description>If you are working with me (even as a directed study student), you will need to do some things for the University and my funding agencies.
I ask that everyone do these things, even if at first they may not be required.
Before you can start officially, you must complete &amp;ldquo;Responsible Conduct of Research&amp;rdquo; Training. https://research.wisc.edu/integrity-and-other-requirements/responsible-conduct-of-research-rcr/
I think it’s a bunch of Canvas quizzes. It shouldn&amp;rsquo;t take long. Please do it ASAP.</description></item><item><title>Interpretting Embeddings With Comparison</title><link>/talks/2021_10_china_embeddings/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2021_10_china_embeddings/</guid><description>Invited Keynote at the CSIG-VIS International Lecture Series (China, virtual).
A recording of the talk is available at: https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1Hv411u7c6
Interpreting Embeddings with Comparison from gleicher</description></item><item><title>Single-query Path Planning Using Sample-efficient Probability Informed Trees</title><link>/video/2021_sprint/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2021_sprint/</guid><description/></item><item><title>CollisionIK: A Per-Instant Method for Generating Robot Motions with Environment Collision Avoidance</title><link>/video/2021_collisionik/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2021_collisionik/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Strobe: An Acceleration Meta-algorithm for Optimizing Robot Paths using Concurrent Interleaved Pods</title><link>/video/2021_strobe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2021_strobe/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reference Letters for Students in Classes</title><link>/posts/no-dwic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 15:06:50 -0600</pubDate><guid>/posts/no-dwic/</guid><description>I will not provide reference letters for students that I know only through a class (as a student).
I get many requests from students from my classes to provide reference (recommendation) letters for graduate school applications. I will not provide these letters.
I will provide letters for students that I get to know outside of regular classes. For example, if you are involved in a directed study project or work with me as a peer mentor for a class (that&amp;rsquo;s why it says &amp;ldquo;as a student&amp;rdquo;).</description></item><item><title/><link>/lunr-search/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/lunr-search/</guid><description> Search Results Waiting for search script to run...</description></item><item><title>Undergrad Research, Projects and Directed Studies</title><link>/pages/advice/undergrad-research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 08:25:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>/pages/advice/undergrad-research/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you are currently an undergraduate and interested in getting involved in a project, please read this. A lot of students seem to be interested in doing &amp;ldquo;research&amp;rdquo; these days, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to set the expectations correctly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Short version: (1) understand research vs. projects; (2) don&amp;rsquo;t do research / directed study until you&amp;rsquo;ve done the requisite coursework; (3) I will say no if you are not a Wisconsin student; (4) consider things to build your portfolio on your own.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Video, Animation and Image Authoring</title><link>/researchtheme/authoring/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 18:49:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>/researchtheme/authoring/</guid><description>Our goal is to make it easier for people to create useable images and video. For example, we have developed methods for improving pictures and video as a post-process (e.g. removing shadows and stabilizing video). We have also worked on adapting imagery for use in new settings (e.g. image and video retargeting or automatic video editing) and making use of large image collections (e.g. intestingness detection or panorama finding).</description></item><item><title>Visualizing English Print</title><link>/researchtheme/vep/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 18:49:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>/researchtheme/vep/</guid><description>To drive our data science efforts, we took a specific application: working with English literature scholars to develop approaches to working with large collections of historical texts.</description></item><item><title>Perceptual Principles for Visualization</title><link>/researchtheme/perceptprinc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 18:49:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>/researchtheme/perceptprinc/</guid><description>Understanding how people see can inform how we should design visualizations. We have been exploring how recent results in perception (e.g., ensemble encoding) can be exploited to create novel visualization designs, and how principles of perception can inform visualization designs.</description></item><item><title>Communicative Characters</title><link>/researchtheme/commchar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 18:49:13 -0500</pubDate><guid>/researchtheme/commchar/</guid><description>We are working on better ways to synthesize human motions to make animated characters (both on screen and robots) that are better able to communicate. Generally, we focus on trying to make use of collections of examples (such as motion capture) to build models that allow us to generate novel movements, or to define models of communicative motions.</description></item><item><title>Usable VR and AR</title><link>/researchtheme/usablearvr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 18:48:50 -0500</pubDate><guid>/researchtheme/usablearvr/</guid><description>Virtual Reality (VR) and Augmented Reality (AR) are interesting display devices that are becoming practical. We are exploring how to design VR and AR applications that can address application tasks, as well as to develop new mechanisms that will make these displays more useful across a broad range of applications.</description></item><item><title>Visualizing Comparisons for Data Science</title><link>/researchtheme/visualcomp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 18:48:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>/researchtheme/visualcomp/</guid><description>Data interpretation tasks often involve making comparisons among the data, or can be thought of as comparisons. We are developing better visualization tools for performing comparisons for various data challenges, as well as to developing better methods for inventing new designs.</description></item><item><title>Interacting with Machine Learning</title><link>/researchtheme/interactlearn/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 18:45:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/researchtheme/interactlearn/</guid><description>People interact with machine learning systems in many ways: they must build them, debug them, diagnose them, decide to trust them, gain insights on their data from them, etc. We are exploring this in both directions: How do we build machine learning tools into interactive data analysis in order to help people interpret large and complex data? How do we build interaction tools that can help people construct and diagnose machine learning models?</description></item><item><title>Bad Page</title><link>/pages/bad-page/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 22:33:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>/pages/bad-page/</guid><description>This is a placeholder for old pages that did not get converted.</description></item><item><title>Communicating Physical Interactions</title><link>/researchtheme/commphysinteractions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/researchtheme/commphysinteractions/</guid><description>We are working on ways for people and robots to communicate to each other about how objects should be manipulated in the world. Manipulations necessarily involve physical interactions (e.g., forces must be applied correctly). We are exploring ways for people to tell robots how to act with appropriate forces (e.g., to teach manipulation skills) as well as for robots to communicate back to people about the actions they are performing.</description></item><item><title>Boxer: Interactive Comparison of Classifiers (Talk Video)</title><link>/video/2020_boxer_talk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2020_boxer_talk/</guid><description>This video was the &amp;ldquo;talk&amp;rdquo; for EuroVis 2020 that presented our paper Boxer: Interactive Comparison of Classifier Results. Because EuroVis was held virtually (due to COVID-19), the talk is this 12 minute video.
For more information see the Boxer Project Page.</description></item><item><title>Boxer: Interactive Comparison of Classifiers (Paper Video)</title><link>/video/2020_boxer-demo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2020_boxer-demo/</guid><description>See also the talk video.</description></item><item><title>List of all pages</title><link>/allpages/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 17:40:34 -0600</pubDate><guid>/allpages/</guid><description>2009 Home Page in Graveyard 2013 Graphics Qual in Graveyard 2013 Graphics Qual - Main Reading List in 2013 Graphics Qual 2013 Qual: Readings from Foundations of Computer Graphics in 2013 Graphics Qual 2013 Qual: Real-Time Rendering in 2013 Graphics Qual 2013 Qual: Surface Parameterization in 2013 Graphics Qual 2013 Qual: Textbooks in 2013 Graphics Qual A Conversation About Visualization in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks A Differential Approach to Graphical Manipulation in Graphics Group Videos A Motion Retargeting Method for Effective Mimicry-based Teleoperation of Robot Arms in Graphics Group Videos About Michael Gleicher (Bio) in Pages Advice in Pages Advice on Prelims and Dissertations (Theses) in Advice Advice on Talks in Advice advice-bibliographies in Graveyard An Autonomous Dynamic Camera Method for Effective Remote Teleoperation in Graphics Group Videos Animation by Adaptation in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Animation by Adaptation: Motion Editing in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Animation by Adaptation: Tales of Motion Use and Re-Use in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Animation by Example in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Animation By Example in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Animation by Example 1: Introduction and Motion Representation in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Animation by Example 2: Motion Signal Processing in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Animation by Example 4: Concatenative Approaches in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Animation by Example 5: Parametric Methods in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Authoring Directed Gaze for Full-body Motion Capture in Graphics Group Videos Automated Extraction and Parameterization of Motions in Large Data Sets in Graphics Group Videos Bad Page in Pages Bad Page Request in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Home Page Boxer: Interactive Comparison of Classifiers (Paper Video) in Graphics Group Videos Boxer: Interactive Comparison of Classifiers (Talk Video) in Graphics Group Videos Briar in Graphics Group Videos Building Efficient, Accurate Character Skins from Examples in Graphics Group Videos Categories in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Home Page Characterizing Input Methods for Human-to-robot Demonstrations in Graphics Group Videos CollisionIK: A Per-Instant Method for Generating Robot Motions with Environment Collision Avoidance in Graphics Group Videos Communicating Physical Interactions in Research Themes Communicative Characters in Research Themes Communicative Robot Motions in Research Themes Comparing Motion Editing Methods in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Computer Animation (CS Computer Club Talk) in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Computer Animation: Its Past, Its Present, And its Future at UW in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Considerations for Visualizing Comparisons in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Content-Preserving Warps for 3D Video Stabilization in Graphics Group Videos courses-games10announce in Graveyard Deformation Sensitive Decimation in Graphics Group Videos Direct Manipulation of Interactive Character Skins in Graphics Group Videos Discovering Panoramas in Web Videos in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Dumb Robots for Smart People in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Editing and Retargetting Animated Motion with Spacetime Constraints in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Effective Replays and Summarization of Virtual Experiences in Graphics Group Videos Evaluating Video-Based Motion Capture in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Explainers: Expert Explorations with Crafted Projections in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Flexible Automatic Motion Blending with Registration Curves in Graphics Group Videos Footskate Cleanup for Motion Capture Editing in Graphics Group Videos From Art and Perception to Visualization and Video in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks from Art and Perception to Visualization, Video, and Virtual Reality in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks GL-HiJacking: Reconstructing from Streams for Stylized Rendering in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Graphics Group Videos in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Home Page Graveyard in Pages HijackGL: Reconstructing from Streams for Stylized Rendering in Graphics Group Videos Human Animation for Interactive Systems in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Human Motion Synthesis by Example in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Image Snapping in Graphics Group Videos Imaging and Visualizing Microvascular Architecture in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Inferring Geometric Constraints in Human Demonstrations in Graphics Group Videos Interacting with Machine Learning in Research Themes Interactive Analysis of Word Vector Embeddings in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Interpreting Embeddings with Comparison in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Interpretting Embeddings With Comparison in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks List of all pages in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Home Page Magic Boards (1) in Graphics Group Videos Magic Boards (2) in Graphics Group Videos Magic Boards (3) in Graphics Group Videos Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Home Page Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Home Page More Motion Capture* in Games: Can we make example-based approaches scale in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Motion Editing and Signal Processing in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Motion Editing with Paths and Tiles in Graphics Group Videos Motion Editing With Spacetime Constraints in Graphics Group Videos Motion Graphs in Graphics Group Videos Motion Path Editing in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Motion Path Editing in Graphics Group Videos Motion Synthesis by Example: Data-Centric Approches for Animating Game Characters in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Motion Transformations with Spacetime Constraints in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Online Real-Time Presentation of Virtual Experiences for External Viewers in Graphics Group Videos Pages in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Home Page Parametric Motion Graphs in Graphics Group Videos Perception, Comparison, and Models for Uncertainty in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Perceptual Principles for Visualization in Research Themes Pictures from Piles of Data: How Graphics, Multimedia, Vision, Visualization, Animation and Cartography All Connect in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Pictures from Piles of Data: How Graphics, Multimedia, Vision, Visualization, Animation and Cartography All Connect in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Pictures from Piles of Data: How Graphics, Multimedia, Vision, Visualization, Animation and Cartography All Connect in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Talks Posts in Mike Gleicher&amp;#39;s Home Page Pre-2010 Papers By Topic in Graveyard Projective Registration with Difference Decomposition in Graphics Group Videos Quack!</description></item><item><title>Dumb Robots for Smart People</title><link>/talks/2019_11_aihri/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2019_11_aihri/</guid><description>Invited Keynote at the AI-HRI Symposium (AAAI Fall Symposium Series)
Dumb Robots for Smart People (Direct Control Interfaces for Robotics) from gleicher</description></item><item><title>Remote Telemanipulation with Adapting Viewpoints in Visually Complex Environments</title><link>/video/2019_rss-camera/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2019_rss-camera/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Shared-Control-Based Bimanual Robot Manipulation</title><link>/video/2019_bimanual/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2019_bimanual/</guid><description>This video demonstrates our system for interactive control of bimanual robots, published in Science Robotics, June 2019.</description></item><item><title>Stampede: A Discrete-Optimization Method for Solving Pathwise-Inverse Kinematics</title><link>/video/2019_stampede/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2019_stampede/</guid><description/></item><item><title>User-Guided Offline Synthesis of Robot Arm Motion from 6-DoF Paths</title><link>/video/2019_userguide/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2019_userguide/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Characterizing Input Methods for Human-to-robot Demonstrations</title><link>/video/2019_tongs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2019_tongs/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Interpreting Embeddings with Comparison</title><link>/talks/2019_01_tuscon2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2019_01_tuscon2/</guid><description>Invited talk at the Computer Science Department Seminar, University of Arizona, Tuscon, January 15, 2019.</description></item><item><title>What Shakespeare Taught Us About Visualization and Data Science</title><link>/talks/2019_01_tuscon1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2019_01_tuscon1/</guid><description>Invited talk at the TRIPODS (Data Science) Seminar, University of Arizona, Tuscon, January 14, 2019. This talk is similar to the previous talk of the same title.</description></item><item><title>Inferring Geometric Constraints in Human Demonstrations</title><link>/video/2018_inferring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2018_inferring/</guid><description/></item><item><title>RelaxedIK: Real-time Synthesis of Accurate and Feasible Robot Arm Motion</title><link>/video/2018_relaxedik/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2018_relaxedik/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Interactive Analysis of Word Vector Embeddings</title><link>/talks/2018_06_embedding/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2018_06_embedding/</guid><description>Paper presentation at EuroVis 2018</description></item><item><title>Perception, Comparison, and Models for Uncertainty</title><link>/talks/2018_06_uncertainty/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2018_06_uncertainty/</guid><description>Invited talk at the EuroRV^3 Uncertainty workshop</description></item><item><title>What Shakespeare Taught Us About Visualization and Data Science</title><link>/talks/2018_05_vienna/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2018_05_vienna/</guid><description>Invited talk at the University of Vienna, May 30, 2018. This talk is similar to the previous talk of the same title.</description></item><item><title>An Autonomous Dynamic Camera Method for Effective Remote Teleoperation</title><link>/video/2018-hri-camera/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2018-hri-camera/</guid><description>This is the video accompaniment to our best-paper award winning paper An Autonomous Dynamic Camera Method for Effective Remote Teleoperation from HRI 2018. It demonstrates a system that allows the user to control a robot manipulator and see what they are doing by having a second robot control a video camera that watches the action.
See also the later video from the system that added more intelligence to the camera control, published at RSS 2019.</description></item><item><title>Considerations for Visualizing Comparisons</title><link>/talks/2017_10_viscomp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2017_10_viscomp/</guid><description/></item><item><title>What Shakespeare Taught Us About Visualization and Data Science</title><link>/talks/2017_07_procomm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2017_07_procomm/</guid><description>Invited keynote at the IEEE Professional Communications Society Meeting</description></item><item><title>Through the Lens of 25 Years: Through-the-Lens Camera Control Revisited</title><link>/talks/2017_04_ttl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2017_04_ttl/</guid><description>Invited Keynote at WICED 2017 (6th Workshop on Intelligent Cinematography and Editing), Lyon, France.</description></item><item><title>A Motion Retargeting Method for Effective Mimicry-based Teleoperation of Robot Arms</title><link>/video/2017_mimicry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2017_mimicry/</guid><description/></item><item><title>What Shakespeare Taught Us About Data Science and Visualization</title><link>/talks/2016_12_jhu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2016_12_jhu/</guid><description>Seminar at Johns Hopkins University, December 2016. A similar talk was given at New York University in October.</description></item><item><title>Authoring Directed Gaze for Full-body Motion Capture</title><link>/video/2016_gazeediting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2016_gazeediting/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Towards Comprehensible Modeling (Human-Centric Issues in Data Analytics)</title><link>/talks/2016_10_bigdata/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2016_10_bigdata/</guid><description>Talk at the Midwest Big Data Workshop at the University of Chicago.</description></item><item><title>Visualization (Tutorial at EMDA)</title><link>/talks/2015_06_emda/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2015_06_emda/</guid><description>An invited tutorial on Visualization at the Early Modern Digital Agendas workshop at the Folger Library, Washington, DC.
1 - Intro 2 - What is Visualization? 3 - Encodings</description></item><item><title>Seeing, Scatterplots and Shakespeare</title><link>/talks/2015_05_portland/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2015_05_portland/</guid><description>Invited talk at Portland State University, May 2015. This talk is an update of the earlier talk with a similar title.</description></item><item><title>Serendip Rank Viewer</title><link>/video/2015_serendiprankview/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2015_serendiprankview/</guid><description>A demonstration of Serendip&amp;rsquo;s RankViewer. Serendip is a corpus exploration tool that uses probabilistic topic modeling as a lens through which to view documents. The demonstration uses a topic model generated on a corpus of 1,080 digitized English texts published between 1530 and 1799.</description></item><item><title>Towards Comprehensible Predictive Modeling</title><link>/talks/2014_11_predict/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2014_11_predict/</guid><description>Talk at the VisWeek 2014 Workshop on Visualization for Predictive Analytics</description></item><item><title>Towards Comprehensible Modeling</title><link>/talks/2014_06_dag/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2014_06_dag/</guid><description>Talk at the Dagstuhl Seminar &amp;ldquo;Scientific Visualization&amp;rdquo;, June 2, 2014</description></item><item><title>Seeing, Scatterplots and Shakespeare: Adventures in Data Visualization</title><link>/talks/2013_11_arc6/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2013_11_arc6/</guid><description>Talk given at the Journée scientifique de l&amp;rsquo;ARC 6 in Grenoble. This was a meeting of researchers from various fields from around the Rhone-Alpes region. (slides 9-up) This talk was also given at the Technische Universitat Wien (Vienna, Austria, December 2013) and INRAI-Saclay (near Paris, February 2014), with very similar slides.</description></item><item><title>Explainers: Expert Explorations with Crafted Projections</title><link>/talks/2013_10_explainers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2013_10_explainers/</guid><description>Talk given at VIS 2013 conference for a VAST (TVCG) paper.</description></item><item><title>Splatterplots: Overcoming Overdraw in Scatter Plots</title><link>/talks/2013_10_splatter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2013_10_splatter/</guid><description>Talk given at VIS 2013 conference for a TVCG journal paper.</description></item><item><title>Splatterplots: Overcoming Overdraw in Scatter Plots</title><link>/video/2013_splatterplots/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2013_splatterplots/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Stylized and Performative Gaze for Character Animation</title><link>/video/2013_stylizedgaze/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2013_stylizedgaze/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Why Evaluate?</title><link>/talks/2012_10_beliv/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2012_10_beliv/</guid><description>Presentation at the BELIV &amp;lsquo;12 workshop (tag team presentation with Miriah, based on conversations with Michael Sedlmair.</description></item><item><title>Online Real-Time Presentation of Virtual Experiences for External Viewers</title><link>/video/2012_realtime_presentvr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2012_realtime_presentvr/</guid><description/></item><item><title>from Art and Perception to Visualization, Video, and Virtual Reality</title><link>/talks/2012_06_france/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2012_06_france/</guid><description>Talk given at INRIA Rhone-Alps (Grenoble, FR) and INRIA Sophia Antipolis (Sophia-Antipolis, FR).</description></item><item><title>Seeing Shakespeare (and Sequences): Making pictures to learn from stuff you don't want to read</title><link>/talks/2012_04_library/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2012_04_library/</guid><description>A talk given at Memorial Library as part of the Humanities Research Bridge.</description></item><item><title>Effective Replays and Summarization of Virtual Experiences</title><link>/video/2012_replayvr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2012_replayvr/</guid><description/></item><item><title>From Art and Perception to Visualization and Video</title><link>/talks/2011_11_cmu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2011_11_cmu/</guid><description>A talk at the CMU Robotics seminar. A video of the talk is on YouTube (availble in HD)!</description></item><item><title>Pictures from Piles of Data: How Graphics, Multimedia, Vision, Visualization, Animation and Cartography All Connect</title><link>/talks/2011_03_ima/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2011_03_ima/</guid><description>A Talk at the Institute for Mathematics and its Applications (IMA) at the University of Minnesota.</description></item><item><title>SubSpace Video Stabilization (ToG 2011)</title><link>/video/2011_subspacestabilization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2011_subspacestabilization/</guid><description>Video from our 2011 Transactions on Graphics Paper.
This system provided a practical approach to warp stabilization. It is the key technical piece that lead to Adobe&amp;rsquo;s Warp Stabilizer.
This work was done with Feng Liu, Michael Gleicher, Jue Wang, Hailin Jin, and Aseem Agarwala.</description></item><item><title>Using Perception to Make Better Pictures</title><link>/talks/2010_05_eri/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2010_05_eri/</guid><description>A Talk at the ERI seminar, University of Wisconsin, Madison (note, this is a shortened version of the Pictures from Piles of Data talk)</description></item><item><title>Pictures from Piles of Data: How Graphics, Multimedia, Vision, Visualization, Animation and Cartography All Connect</title><link>/talks/2010_02_physics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2010_02_physics/</guid><description>A Talk at the Chaos and Complexity seminar, University of Wisconsin, Madison</description></item><item><title>A Conversation About Visualization</title><link>/talks/2009_12_hackerwith/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2009_12_hackerwith/</guid><description>A talk at The Hacker Within monthly meeting.</description></item><item><title>Pictures from Piles of Data: How Graphics, Multimedia, Vision, Visualization, Animation and Cartography All Connect</title><link>/talks/2009_07_navtec/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2009_07_navtec/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Content-Preserving Warps for 3D Video Stabilization</title><link>/video/2009_warp_stable/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2009_warp_stable/</guid><description>This is a video demonstration from our SIGGRAPH 2009 paper &amp;ldquo;Content-Preserving Warps for 3D Video Stabilization&amp;rdquo;. This is an early predecessor to the technology that became Adobe&amp;rsquo;s Warp Stabilizer (although, that is really based on a later paper).</description></item><item><title>Discovering Panoramas in Web Videos</title><link>/talks/2008_10_pano/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2008_10_pano/</guid><description>Presentation at ACM Multimedia 2008</description></item><item><title>Motion Synthesis by Example: Data-Centric Approches for Animating Game Characters</title><link>/talks/2008_10_utah/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2008_10_utah/</guid><description>Distinguished Lecture at the University of Utah Computer Sciences Department. Note: because of the slide animation, some of this doesn&amp;rsquo;t look so great in print form.</description></item><item><title>Synthesis by Example: Connecting Motion Planning and Example-Based Movement</title><link>/talks/2008_07_sigcourse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2008_07_sigcourse/</guid><description>Presentation at SIGGRAPH 2008 course &amp;ldquo;Motion Planning and Autonomy for Virtual Humans.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>More Motion Capture* in Games: Can we make example-based approaches scale</title><link>/talks/2008_06_utrecht/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2008_06_utrecht/</guid><description>Presentation at the Motion in Games Workshop, Utrecht, June 2008.</description></item><item><title>Re-Cinematography (2007)</title><link>/video/2008_recinematography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2008_recinematography/</guid><description>This video demonstrates Re-Cinematography - our approach for post-process video stabilization that tries to produce high-quality camera motions. The original paper (at MultiMedia 2007) won the &amp;ldquo;best in track award,&amp;rdquo; and was invited to be extended as a journal paper in TOMCCAP.
Note: this is taken from a &amp;ldquo;FLV&amp;rdquo; file so, at one point it was highly compressed using 2007 technology. It was before we had reliable H.264 (or better).</description></item><item><title>Re-Cinematography: Improving the Camera Dynamics of Casual Video</title><link>/talks/2007_09_recin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2007_09_recin/</guid><description>Presentation at ACM Multimedia 2007 in the Best Papers Session.</description></item><item><title>Parametric Motion Graphs</title><link>/video/2007_pmg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2007_pmg/</guid><description>We present an example-based motion synthesis technique that generates continuous streams of high-fidelity, controllable motion for interactive applications, such as video games.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Videography</title><link>/video/2007_vv-mm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2007_vv-mm/</guid><description>We present automated system called Virtual Videography that employs the art of videography to mimic videographer-produced lecture videos, while being unobtrusive when recording.
The system is described in a 2007 Paper.</description></item><item><title>Splicing Upper-Body Actions with Locomotion</title><link>/video/2006_splicing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2006_splicing/</guid><description>We present a simple and efficient technique for synthesizing high-fidelity motions by attaching, or splicing,the upper-body action of one motion example to the lower-body locomotion of another.</description></item><item><title>Human Motion Synthesis by Example</title><link>/talks/2004_11_gametech/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2004_11_gametech/</guid><description>A Talk Given at the Game Technologies Seminar. This is really the first part of a tag-team talk given with Lucas. Originally it was scheduled for a longer period of time, so most of the slides were skipped in order to cram it into 75 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Automated Extraction and Parameterization of Motions in Large Data Sets</title><link>/video/2004_parammotions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2004_parammotions/</guid><description>We provide automated methods for identifying logically similar motions in a data set and using them to build a continuous and intuitively parameterized space of motions.</description></item><item><title>Animation by Example</title><link>/talks/2004_06_korea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2004_06_korea/</guid><description>An overview talk given at both Seoul National University and KAIST (Korean Advanced Institute for Science and Technology).</description></item><item><title>Animation by Example 1: Introduction and Motion Representation</title><link>/talks/2004_05_1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2004_05_1/</guid><description>Lecture given at the Workshop on Image Processing and Related Issues at Zhejiang University. This lecture was the first 2 parts of 5 (it was given as a 2 hour lecture with a break in the middle).</description></item><item><title>Animation by Example 2: Motion Signal Processing</title><link>/talks/2004_05_2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2004_05_2/</guid><description>Lecture given at the Workshop on Image Processing and Related Issues at Zheziang University. This lecture was the 3 part of 5.</description></item><item><title>Animation by Example 4: Concatenative Approaches</title><link>/talks/2004_05_3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2004_05_3/</guid><description>Lecture given at the Workshop on Image Processing and Related Issues at Zhejiang University. This lecture was part 4 of 5.</description></item><item><title>Animation by Example 5: Parametric Methods</title><link>/talks/2004_05_4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2004_05_4/</guid><description>Lecture given at the Workshop on Image Processing and Related Issues at Zhejiang University. This lecture was part 5 of 5.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Videography 2004 (early result)</title><link>/video/2004_vv04/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2004_vv04/</guid><description>Note: see the Virtual Videography video page for a more recent result.</description></item><item><title>Magic Boards (1)</title><link>/video/2003_magicboard1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2003_magicboard1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Magic Boards (2)</title><link>/video/2003_magicboard2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2003_magicboard2/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Magic Boards (3)</title><link>/video/2003_magicboard3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2003_magicboard3/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Imaging and Visualizing Microvascular Architecture</title><link>/talks/2003_11_cibm2003/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2003_11_cibm2003/</guid><description>Seminar presented at the CIBM seminar series, November 11, 2003. Talk split with co-PI Garet Lahvis.</description></item><item><title>Stylizing Motion with Drawings</title><link>/video/2003_cartoon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2003_cartoon/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Building Efficient, Accurate Character Skins from Examples</title><link>/video/2003_efficientskins/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2003_efficientskins/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Deformation Sensitive Decimation</title><link>/video/2003_decimation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2003_decimation/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Flexible Automatic Motion Blending with Registration Curves</title><link>/video/2003_regcurves/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2003_regcurves/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Motion Editing with Paths and Tiles</title><link>/video/2003_tiles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2003_tiles/</guid><description>This video shows off work we did in 2003, but was never published. The student graduated before we were able to complete the paper.</description></item><item><title>Direct Manipulation of Interactive Character Skins</title><link>/video/2003_directskin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2003_directskin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Snap Together Motion: Assembling Run-Time Animation</title><link>/video/2003_stm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2003_stm/</guid><description>We present an approach to character motion called Snap-Together Motion that addresses the unique demands of virtual environments. Snap-Together Motion (STM) preprocesses a corpus of motion capture examples into a set of short clips that can be concatenated to make continuous streams of motion.</description></item><item><title>Human Animation for Interactive Systems</title><link>/talks/2003_03_texas2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2003_03_texas2/</guid><description>This is a talk given at the University of Texas, Austin and at Sony (August 2003).</description></item><item><title>Virtual Videography (2003 early version)</title><link>/video/2003_vv/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2003_vv/</guid><description>The main idea behind Virtual Videography is to automatically edit video of some event that would be nice to record, but too costly or intrusive to place a camera crew, such as a classroom lecture. (Note: Newer video at Virtual Videography).</description></item><item><title>Animation By Example</title><link>/talks/2002_10_animbyexample/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2002_10_animbyexample/</guid><description>Seminar presented various places (including Illinois, IBM, Stanford, Pixar, Michigan, Penn)</description></item><item><title>Footskate Cleanup for Motion Capture Editing</title><link>/video/2002_footskate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2002_footskate/</guid><description>Video from our 2002 paper &amp;ldquo;Footskate cleanup for motion capture editing&amp;rdquo;. This work was published at the Symposium on Computer Animation.
Many motion capture editing operations result in the feet of the character moving when they ought to remain planted. We present a simple, efficient algorithm for removing this footskate.</description></item><item><title>Motion Graphs</title><link>/video/2002_mographs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2002_mographs/</guid><description/></item><item><title>HijackGL: Reconstructing from Streams for Stylized Rendering</title><link>/video/2002_hijackgl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2002_hijackgl/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Evaluating Video-Based Motion Capture</title><link>/talks/2002_06_videomocap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2002_06_videomocap/</guid><description>Presented at Computer Animation 2002</description></item><item><title>GL-HiJacking: Reconstructing from Streams for Stylized Rendering</title><link>/talks/2002_06_npar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2002_06_npar/</guid><description>Presented at NPAR 2002</description></item><item><title>Computer Animation: Its Past, Its Present, And its Future at UW</title><link>/talks/2001_12_csclub/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2001_12_csclub/</guid><description>Talk for the CS Club to introduce what we do at Wisconsin.</description></item><item><title>Simplicial Families of Drawings</title><link>/video/2001_simplicial/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2001_simplicial/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Animation by Adaptation: Tales of Motion Use and Re-Use</title><link>/talks/2001_07_osu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2001_07_osu/</guid><description>Presented at Advanced Center for Computing in the Arts and Design,Ohio State University, July 2001</description></item><item><title>Animation by Adaptation: Motion Editing</title><link>/talks/2001_05_ima-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2001_05_ima-tutorial/</guid><description>Presented at the Computer Graphics Tutorial at the Institute for Mathematics and Its Applications at the University of Minnesota.</description></item><item><title>Quack! Quick! We need a Dancing Duck! Tales of Motion Use and Re-Use</title><link>/talks/2001_05_ima-wkshp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2001_05_ima-wkshp/</guid><description>Presented at the Computer Graphics Workshop at the Institute for Mathematics and Its Applications.</description></item><item><title>Motion Path Editing</title><link>/talks/2001_03_path/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2001_03_path/</guid><description>Presented at the 2001 Symposium on Interactive 3D graphics</description></item><item><title>Motion Path Editing</title><link>/video/2001_pathediting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/2001_pathediting/</guid><description>Warning: this is a poor quality AVI upload.</description></item><item><title>Animation by Adaptation</title><link>/talks/2001_02_animationbyadaptation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2001_02_animationbyadaptation/</guid><description>Distinguished Lecture, Department of Computer Science, University of Virginia</description></item><item><title>Comparing Motion Editing Methods</title><link>/talks/2000_06_comparingmoedit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/2000_06_comparingmoedit/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Computer Animation (CS Computer Club Talk)</title><link>/talks/1999_10_ugradtalk99/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/1999_10_ugradtalk99/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Motion Editing and Signal Processing</title><link>/talks/1999_07_sigcourse/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/1999_07_sigcourse/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Motion Transformations with Spacetime Constraints</title><link>/talks/1999_03_spring99/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/1999_03_spring99/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Retargetting Motion to New Characters</title><link>/video/1998_st-retarget/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 1998 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/1998_st-retarget/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Spacetime Swing</title><link>/video/1998_st-swing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 1998 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/1998_st-swing/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Retargeting Motion to New Characters</title><link>/talks/1998_07_retarget/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 1998 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/1998_07_retarget/</guid><description>SIGGRAPH &amp;lsquo;98 talk (both left and right slide decks in one file)</description></item><item><title>Editing and Retargetting Animated Motion with Spacetime Constraints</title><link>/talks/1998_04_jobtalk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 1998 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/1998_04_jobtalk/</guid><description>My 1998 Job Talk (good enough to get me a job at Wisconsin!)</description></item><item><title>Projective Registration with Difference Decomposition</title><link>/video/1997_tracking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/1997_tracking/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Retargeting Motion to New Characters</title><link>/talks/1997_03_moedit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/talks/1997_03_moedit/</guid><description>I3D 1997 talk (scanned from 35mm slides)</description></item><item><title>Motion Editing With Spacetime Constraints</title><link>/video/1997_st-moedit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 1997 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/1997_st-moedit/</guid><description>Yes. This really was all in real-time on a circa 1996 Macintosh. I have no idea how I made it go so fast.
This video is from the 1997 Interactive 3D Symposium Paper. An earlier version of the paper actually appeared as a 1998 journal paper. The journal paper mainly has 2D examples, and focuses on the non-interactive cases.</description></item><item><title>Image Snapping</title><link>/video/1995_snapping/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 1995 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/1995_snapping/</guid><description/></item><item><title>A Differential Approach to Graphical Manipulation</title><link>/video/1994_thesis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 1994 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/1994_thesis/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Through-the-Lens Camera Control</title><link>/video/1992_ttl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 1992 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/1992_ttl/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Briar</title><link>/video/1991_briar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 1991 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/video/1991_briar/</guid><description/></item><item><title/><link>/sectionlinks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sectionlinks/</guid><description> Home Papers Talks Videos Advice</description></item><item><title>2009 Home Page</title><link>/pages/graveyard/2009-home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/graveyard/2009-home/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is an Ancient (2009) version of my home page.
Page last modified on July 16, 2009, at 11:52 AM.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2013 Graphics Qual - Main Reading List</title><link>/pages/graveyard/qual2013/qual2013-qual2013/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/graveyard/qual2013/qual2013-qual2013/</guid><description>&lt;p>2013 Graphics Qual - main reading list.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2013 Qual: Readings from Foundations of Computer Graphics</title><link>/pages/graveyard/qual2013/qual2013-fcg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/graveyard/qual2013/qual2013-fcg/</guid><description>&lt;p>Textbook readings - materials from an undergrad class.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2013 Qual: Real-Time Rendering</title><link>/pages/graveyard/qual2013/qual2013-rtr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/graveyard/qual2013/qual2013-rtr/</guid><description>&lt;p>2013 Graphics Qual - readings from the Real Time Rendering book.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2013 Qual: Surface Parameterization</title><link>/pages/graveyard/qual2013/qual2013-surfaceparam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/graveyard/qual2013/qual2013-surfaceparam/</guid><description>&lt;p>2013 Graphics Qual - readings on surface parameterization.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2013 Qual: Textbooks</title><link>/pages/graveyard/qual2013/qual2013-texts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/graveyard/qual2013/qual2013-texts/</guid><description>&lt;p>Textbook reading for the 2013 Graphics Qual.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About Michael Gleicher (Bio)</title><link>/pages/bio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/bio/</guid><description>(or look at my C.V.)
One paragraph standard professional bio One paragraph profession bio - 2019 Michael Gleicher is a Professor in the Department of Computer Sciences at the University of Wisconsin, Madison. Prof. Gleicher is founder of the Department&amp;rsquo;s Visual Computing Group. He co-directs both the Visual Computing Laboratory and the Collaborative Robotics Laboratory at UW-Madison. His research interests span the range of visual computing, including data visualization, robotics, and virtual reality.</description></item><item><title>Advice on Prelims and Dissertations (Theses)</title><link>/pages/advice/prelimsandthesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/advice/prelimsandthesis/</guid><description>I have pretty strong opinions on what a thesis should be. My opinion might matter to you (if you want me to sign off), but they might be a generally good way to think about writing anything.</description></item><item><title>Advice on Talks</title><link>/pages/advice/talks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/advice/talks/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have written some advice on how to give a talk - that is the basis for a lecture in my grad classes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>advice-bibliographies</title><link>/pages/graveyard/bibliographies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/graveyard/bibliographies/</guid><description>Reading is an important part of doing research.
Part of the problem is keeping track of what you&amp;rsquo;ve read. I strongly recommend that you keep a bibliography (database) of everything you read that is research/work related.
Update: back when I wrote this, there weren&amp;rsquo;t any good technological solutions to this. That has changed a bit. As of 2020, I am using Zotero. Medeley is in some ways a better alternative, but there are issues that the company that runs it treats your data in an unacceptable manner.</description></item><item><title>Bad Page Request</title><link>/badpage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/badpage/</guid><description>The URL that you were looking for was on my old web site.
In Summer of 2020, I began the project of rebuilding my website. Almost all pages from the old site have been recreated, but there are not necessarily redirects to the new pages.
You&amp;rsquo;ll have to look around a bit to find out where things have gone.</description></item><item><title>courses-games10announce</title><link>/pages/graveyard/courses-games10announce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/graveyard/courses-games10announce/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a historic announcement for the 2010 Computer Games Class. It was the first time I taught the class.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pre-2010 Papers By Topic</title><link>/pages/graveyard/oldpapersbytopic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/graveyard/oldpapersbytopic/</guid><description>Selected Historical Publications (Papers, Talks, Videos), Organized by Topic This page has not been updated since 2010! Please See http://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~gleicher/Papers for an up to date list!
This list is not necessarily complete, and hasn&amp;rsquo;t been updated in quite some time. For a more complete list, check the automatically generated lists of papers, talks, or videos. This is mainly things from the past few years.
1. Visualization and Protein Science 1.1 Bioinformatics Visualizations (Sequences) 1.</description></item><item><title>Re-cinematography</title><link>/pages/graveyard/re-cinematography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/graveyard/re-cinematography/</guid><description>Re-Cinematography was our circa 2007 video stabilization system. At the time, it was way better than anything else. It inspired later techniques, notably our 2009 3D Warping technique, and our 2010 Subspace Warping technique (which evolved into the Adobe Warp Stabilizer.).
Re-Cinematography pushed the limits of what could be done with 2D global warps (using a single, 8 parameter projective warp over the entire image). The later techniques (e.g. SubSpace Video Stabilization (ToG 2011)) went beyond it by allowing for warping the image, not just global deformations.</description></item><item><title>Status Reports</title><link>/pages/advice/statusreports/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/advice/statusreports/</guid><description>&lt;div id="wikitext">
&lt;p>If you work for me (for example, as an RA or an undergrad directed study) you must send me a status report every week.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Graduate School FAQ</title><link>/pages/advice/gradschoolfaq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/advice/gradschoolfaq/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is advice for undergraduates who are thinking about going to graduate school. There is specific advice for students who are applying to Wisconsin, and even more specifically, might like to work with me.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Visualization 2010 Course Announcement</title><link>/pages/graveyard/vis10announce/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/graveyard/vis10announce/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the historic announcement for the first time I offered a visualization class in 2010. It was an experiment that keeps going to this day (2020 as I write this). It&amp;rsquo;s pretty interesting that even at the beginning, I had the same ideas as to the goals of the class.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Write-Ups for Directed Study Projects (699s)</title><link>/pages/advice/writeups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/advice/writeups/</guid><description>&lt;p>Making a final writeup for your directed study project (or summer intern project, or honors thesis project, or &amp;hellip;) is important. Reflecting on what you&amp;rsquo;ve done is an important part of the learning process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Writing Advice: The Paper "Recipe"</title><link>/pages/advice/paperrecipe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/advice/paperrecipe/</guid><description>Let me tell you a little trick that I tell all the students: &lt;strong>sentence, paragraph, page&lt;/strong></description></item></channel></rss>